South Park: Joining the Panderverse is a animation, comedy,
science fiction film directed by Trey Parker.
Cartman's deeply disturbing dreams portend the end
of the life he knows and loves.
Meanwhile, the adults in South Park are wrestling with their own life
decisions, as the advent of AI is turning their world upside down.
Various Characters (voice), played by Trey Parker.
Various Characters (voice), played by Matt Stone.
Sharon Marsh / Shelly Marsh / Liane Cartman / Alien Liane
Cartman (voice), played by April Stewart.
Kathleen Kennedy / Panderverse Mitch Murphy (voice), played by Kimberly Brooks.
Sheila Broflovski (voice), played by Mona Marshall.
Steve Black (voice), played by Adrien Beard.
"South Park: Joining the Panderverse" is a 2023 American adult
animated comedy television special episode.
It is the fifth South Park television special, and the
326th episode of the series overall.
The special premiered on October 27, 2023 on Paramount+.
The episode parodies The Walt Disney Company, CEO Robert "Bob" Iger and Lucasfilm President Kathleen Kennedy in particular, and
the perceived practice of producing formulaic films exhibiting "forced wokeness", for reasons of identity politics.
The story depicts fourth-grader Eric Cartman as he is transported to another universe in which all of South Park's residents are racially diverse women opposed to the
patriarchy, while a version of Kennedy that resembles Cartman is depicted frequently tampering with Disney's productions by demanding inclusion of minority groups.
The film explores themes of artificial intelligence (a.i.), satire,
social satire, adult animation, political satire.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and thought_provoking.